Bryce C. Turner

Senior Research Assistant • Federal Reserve Board (Remote) • Boston, MA
Phone: 203-524-2090 • Email: mailto:

BCTurner20@gmail.comB.C.Turner20@gmail.com • Citizenship: USA

SUMMARY

[topsep=3pt,itemsep=2pt,partopsep=0pt, parsep=0pt, leftmargin=*]Detailed analyst with over 2 years of experience developing public databases, anticipating problems and implementing fixes before systems fail. Creative thinker with over 3 years testing hypotheses and telling stories using statistical analysis and econometrics.

EXPERIENCE

[topsep=3pt,itemsep= 2pt,partopsep=0pt, parsep= 0pt, leftmargin = *]Federal Reserve Board of Governors Washington, DC Senior Research Assistant • Flow of Funds Section March 2018 - Present[topsep=1pt,itemsep= 3pt,partopsep=0pt, parsep= 0pt, leftmargin = *]

- Developed, streamlined, and overhauled data processes for Financial Accounts of the United States and other public-facing projects.
 Proposed and implemented process changes and new data sources to increase accuracy. Enhanced knowledge of several statistical languages, especially R.
- Collaborated across Federal Reserve System to develop materials for Board Briefings, Internal Presentations, and ad-hoc Policy Projects.
 Presented results orally and in writing.
- Explored new research initiatives, spearheaded important analyses, and co-authored two academic papers.

Major Projects

[topsep=2pt,itemsep=3pt,partopsep=0pt, parsep=0pt, leftmargin = *]

CLOs in the Financial Accounts Examined and verified conflicting data sources to understand market size. Organized and presented findings for internal dissemination.

Monetary Policy Research Paper Expanded existing project to measure Mortgage Lenders' responses to Monetary Policy, demonstrating self-motivation and creativity. Spearheaded analysis and created visualizations for use in paper and presentations. Strengthened knowledge of econometric techniques.

Wealth Effect Research Paper Designed creative econometric technique to study effect of wealth on productivity. Collaborated with co-author to verify findings, display results, and write sections of paper.

Conversion of Insurance Bond Holdings Converted Insurance Bond Holdings from Book Value to Market Value. Developed flexible tools in R to reliably extract information from messy underlying data sources. Enhanced subsequent projects by increasing usability of data source.

Section 529 Plans Overhauled process for calculating and presenting of Section 529 Plan assets. Saved dozens of man-hours per year and increased process reliability. Learned regular expressions in R.

The Stanton Foundation

Cambridge, MA

Program Analyst

January 2017 - August 2017

[topsep=1pt,itemsep= 3pt,partopsep=0pt, parsep= 0pt, leftmargin = *]

- Constructed data pipeline to oversee and evaluate grant program distributing over \$1M. Published results in K9 Cop Magazine and penned memo to Board on cost-efficiency and viability of program.
- Examined empirical literature on Discount Factors in Private Equity Valuations. Presented findings in writing and in person to Board of Directors and Outside Counsel.

Wayfair, Inc.

Boston, MA

Claims and Logistics Co-Op

January 2015 - June 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

[topsep=3pt,itemsep=2pt,partopsep=0pt, parsep=0pt, leftmargin=*]Advanced R, Advanced Stata, Advanced Excel, Intermediate \LaTeX , Intermediate Python, Intermediate \LaTeX

PRESENTATIONS

[topsep=3pt,itemsep=2pt,partopsep=0pt, parsep=0pt, leftmargin = *]CLOs in the Financial Accounts

May 2019

Federal Reserve Board • with Youngsuk Yook Discount Factors in Private Equity Valuations

June 2017

The Stanton Foundation Board of Directors

PAPERS AND PUBLICATIONS

[topsep=3pt,itemsep=2pt,partopsep=2pt, parsep=2pt, leftmargin = *] Non-banks, Banks, and Monetary Policy: U.S. Loan-Level Evidence since the 1990s

(with David Elliott, Ralf R. Meisenzahl and José-Luis Peydró) A Stroke of Luck: Estimating the Effect of Wealth on Worker Productivity (with Joseph Briggs) The Cost of Operating a K9 Unit, K9 Cop Magazine, Summer 2017 Edition

EDUCATION

 $[topsep=3pt, itemsep=2pt, partopsep=0pt, parsep=0pt, leftmargin=*] \textbf{Northeastern University} \\ B.S. \ in \ Economics \bullet Minor \ in \ Mathematics \\ Cum \ Laude$